So we've talked a lot about all the different benefits and the power
of adopting a structured approach to problem solving.
You save more time. You're much more deliberate about your approach.
You know exactly where you are in the process. There are many other benefits.
But I'm curious, Marc: do you always take
the same structured approach to solving problems?
No, it definitely varies depending upon the context.
In some cases — if we're doing a new product introduction, for example — it might be
a design-thinking approach. If there is a lot of data involved, it might be an advanced-analytics approach.
Generally, there are five different approaches
we typically see in problem solving.
There is the hypothesis-led approach, which we're going
to go into a lot more detail on in this course.
But there are also many others. There is the domain-IP-led approach.
There's the advanced-analytics approach.
There's the design-thinking approach, and there's the engineering approach.
And depending upon the context of the problem, one approach may be better than another.
And then I think another point is, you don't always just use one approach.
Again, depending upon the context, sometimes it's the combination of different approaches
which would get you to the right answer —
or, in some cases, the answer more quickly.
I love what you said, Marc, because I actually think what is super interesting
is that these five different problem-solving approaches,
though the approaches might be a little bit different, their underlying characteristics
are all actually very similar. They all share some common characteristics.
They all have a very focused problem statement.
They're all impact-oriented.
They always take a stakeholder perspective. They're fact-based.
And they also focus on synthesis.
These characteristics underpin every single one
of these different problem-solving approaches.